<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>meta on Ryan Faulhaber</title><link>/tags/meta/</link><description>Recent content in meta on Ryan Faulhaber</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 10:43:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Some notes on techno-pessimism</title><link>/posts/notes-on-techno-pessimism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 10:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/notes-on-techno-pessimism/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve become entralled by Emacs. Part of the reason why I think is because, among other reasons, Emacs represents a lost horizon for what a computer program could be.
Emacs is easy to customize (assuming you know Lisp, which anymore may be a big assumption), and in my experience, easier than Atom or VS Code. In fact, I feel that I can do more in ten lines of Lisp than I can do in 100 of a JavaScript extension for VS Code.</description></item><item><title>My Advent of Code 2020 So Far</title><link>/posts/aoc-2020-so-far/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 14:53:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/aoc-2020-so-far/</guid><description>This is my first year participating in Advent of Code. I enjoy doing coding challenges but I&amp;rsquo;m not competitive about it, so I tend to use them as a learning opportunity. Like for most people, the end of the year is a time of reflection, and when I look back on what I wanted to do this year, I often found myself saying &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s a language I wish I knew better.</description></item><item><title>Critique of the Magic of Modern IDEs</title><link>/posts/critique-of-modern-ides/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 13:19:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/critique-of-modern-ides/</guid><description>The StackOverflow blog recently posted this article asking why so many people continue to use Vim and Emacs when modern editors like Atom exist. This is a question I have personally addressed before with regards to Emacs, but I want to address this post specifically because I think it gets at a commonly held misunderstanding about these editors.
The basic point of the post explores why people would want to use an antiquated editor like Vim or Emacs, and that those who continue to use either are missing out on the so-called magic of a newer IDE.</description></item></channel></rss>